Hallo und herzlich willkommen. Mein
Name ist Elena und ich werde heute
mit euch das Webinar machen. Ja,
heute geht es um Englisch, die
Abiturreihe, Components of Fictional
Text, Bausteine fiktionaler Texte.
Genau, ich werde jetzt gleich als
allererstes einmal mit euch, also die
Folien euch vorstellen, generell über
das Thema sprechen. Zwischendurch
wird es ein paar kleine Aufgaben
geben und am Ende beantworte ich auch
gerne noch. nochmal fragen. Ihr könnt
natürlich zwischendurch auch schon
Fragen stellen oder auch am Ende, da
kann ich euch, also da fordere ich
euch direkt nochmal auf, Fragen zu
stellen. Ich kann auch gerne immer
noch, wenn ich am Ende bin, ein paar
Folien zurückgehen, wie ihr möchtet.
Also wenn irgendwas unklar ist, sagt
Bescheid. Ich gehe dann gerne nochmal
zurück, erkläre gerne nochmal auf
eine andere Art und Weise, wenn ihr
was noch noch nicht verstanden habt.
Sagt nur Bescheid. Gut. Ich hoffe,
ihr könnt mich alle gut verstehen.
Und genau. Also, wenn irgendwas ist,
schreibt gerne in die Chatbox. Ja,
dann werde ich darauf aufmerksam und
kann es, wie gesagt, nochmal anders
erklären. So. Ich werde das Webinar,
also es ist, die Texte, die werden
auf Englisch sein. Wenn ihr möchtet,
kann ich das Webinar auf Englisch
halten. Ich kann es aber auch auf
Deutsch halten, wie ihr mögt. Sagt
einmal Bescheid, auf welcher Sprache
ihr das gerne hören möchtet. Auf
Englisch, okay, gut. Okay, so let's
start. If you don't understand my
English very well, if I should
explain something in a different way
or in German, please tell me. I would
love to explain something in German
to you if you don't understand my
English. Okay, Component.
So, I'm going to read that out first
and then I'm going to explain it in
my own words. In order to analyze a
fictional text, you need knowledge of
the fundamental components that a
fictional text contains. These
elements are used by the author to
create his own fictional word where
the story takes place. They are not
always obvious, therefore they need
to be analyzed in detail. Important
elements are Setting and Atmosphere,
Characters and the Plot. Okay, here I
just, there's nothing I can like add.
So the most important things of
fictional text are like the setting,
so where does take place the
atmosphere, like how are the persons
feeling or is it like dark or how's
the atmosphere, like in general, the
characters and the plot, like what's
happening. Yeah.
So, Setting and Atmosphere, let's
explore that. Setting. The setting
used in a fictional text describes
time as well as the geographic
location. It answers the question of
where and when. The setting can
influence the character's behavior.
It helps to initiate the mood for a
story. So, like, the setting is
important. Like, it's not only where
it does take place, but when. So,
also the time. It's also important,
like, this also contains... Setting.
Setting can influence the character's
behavior, so it's a very important
fact. And it also is important, the
setting can also affect the mood, the
mood of a story, the mood of certain
persons in a story. So it's also
important. Important questions
referring to the setting are which
year or period does the narration
take place in? Which season is it?
Like, I don't know, autumn, spring,
whatever. What time of the day is it?
Is it like noon? Is it like...
Because the weather is also important
as if it's raining or if the sun is
coming out, whatever. It also affects
the setting as maybe there may be
sunshine or rain and it may be dark.
So the setting can change. if the
weather changes. How can the social
environment be described? Like the
social relation between the
characters, for example. Whatever.
Atmosphere. The atmosphere of a story
describes the mood, emotions and
feelings. It is a literary technique
that can provide the reader with a
type of feelings that he gets while
reading the narrative. The atmosphere
can change throughout the story,
especially when there is a change of
setting. As the setting contributes,
So, first, the atmosphere of a story
contains three main things. The mood
of certain persons, it's unique. The
emotions and feelings. So, then
there's also the fact that the
atmosphere can change. So, it's not
static. So, when the story begins and
when the story ends, the mood, the
atmosphere doesn't have to be the
same, so it can be different. The
main purpose of creating a particular
atmosphere in a story is to establish
an emotional effect. Very important.
Therefore, the reader tends to stay
interested in the story as it appears
to be more lively and exciting. So,
yeah, the atmosphere is used to
create a certain tension, Spannung,
in the story. So it's very important
that the atmosphere is well
described, so the story gets more
lively and exciting for the reader to
read. The place where a story takes
place can indicate the spiritual
condition of a character, where
elements like nature, weather, colors
and shapes have an influence on the
mood. Ja, also die Setting, wie ich
es vorhin beschrieben habe, hat einen
Effekt auf die Bedingungen eines
Charakters, wie ist der Charakter,
wie ist er bekannt, oder ist der
Charakter in einem guten Mood oder so
etwas. Aber die Elemente wie Natur,
Wetter, Farben und Formen, sie
beeinflussen den Mood, wie fühlen die
Menschen zum Beispiel, wie ist die
Geschichte vermittelt. example so
dies vor allem ins half ein flüssiges
modus world fast
so passend aus konzernen setting and
atmosphere can be so hier auf die
possible task you may see in your
exam oh yeah in it they could be in
every exam yeah in every oral exam
whatever heißt die atmosphäre in der
text kreis
Wie wurde der
Autor erschaffen? Erklär deine
Meinung mit Beweis vom Text. Also
alle Punkte, die wir, wie ich es
vorher beschrieben habe, sind wichtig
für diese, um diese Fragen zu
beantworten. Also, die Atmosphäre und
die Atmosphäre sind nicht, sie sind
nicht, sie enthalten nicht nur einen
Fakt. Sie sind sehr, wie große
Fakten, also sie enthalten, zum
Beispiel, Farbe, wie die Wetter, was
auch immer, ich habe es bereits
vorhin erklärt, but they are very
important for a story. So if you get
asked, for example, how is the
atmosphere in the text created by the
author? You can say, for example,
yeah, the weather is good, the
weather is bad, whatever. You can
describe it if the sun shines, if
it's raining, if there's a
thunderstorm. What time of the day is
it? For example, you can describe all
these facts to describe better in
detail, to get more points, for
example. Wenn du es in Detail
beschreibst, ist das besser für deine
Grätsch. Phrasen. Mögliche Phrasen,
die du benutzen kannst. Setting. Die
Geschichte nimmt Platz in. Die
Geschichte nimmt Platz in der Zeit,
zum Beispiel in der Zeit der
Zweiten Weltkrieg. Zum Beispiel. Die
Weise, in der die Aktion ist.
Ein bisschen... ...was auch immer.
Die Aktion schafft sich von...
...zu... So all these phrases are so
-called useful phrases you can use in
your exam to start the description of
the setting. Atmosphere. Useful
phrases for the atmosphere. The fact
that creates a warm or friendly,
cold, happy, sinister, frozen,
hostile atmosphere. There is a change
of atmosphere when, for example, when
the king enters. The atmosphere is
charged with anger. The friendly,
warm, cold, whatever, atmosphere has
an impact on. So these are useful
phrases to describe the atmosphere.
Exercise, so first exercise. Please
read the text. I will read it out
loud. Scene 1, so it's from Sam
Shepard, True West. Scene 1, night,
sound of crickets and dark.
Candlelight appears in alcove.
So, the question
for you is, how does the setting
contribute to the mood of scene one?
So, please write in the chat box,
like, what is your opinion? Please
answer or try. um die Frage zu
beantworten. Nenne einfach nur ein
oder zwei Aspekte. Ich brauche nicht
die volle Runde. Nur ein oder zwei
Gedanken, die genügend sind.
Vielleicht haben Sie einige dieser
Ideen. Ich warte auf Antworten. Zum
Beispiel,
schau, wie die Beschreibung
geschrieben wird. Ist es friedlich?
Ist es verletzbar? ist es? Ich weiß
es nicht. Lest es und vielleicht habt
ihr eine Idee.
Also, ich habe eine Antwort bekommen.
Moonlight bedeutet friedlich. Das ist
richtig. Also, ich denke, ich würde
die Exzertion
beenden, dass es sehr friedlich ist
und die Atmosphäre so ein schönes und
friedliches Es ist ein sehr ruhiges
Setting, wie ein Handtuch, ein
Zigarettenstrahl. Es ist so, als
wären sie in keinem Ruck. Sie haben
Zeit, sie sind kalt. Ein Kabelstuhl,
das auf dem Tisch bricht. Das ist
auch ein bisschen romantisch. Es ist
also eine sehr ruhige Atmosphäre, in
der man sich gut fühlen kann.
Wenn man die Description nicht lesen
kann, You get maybe a different sense
of what they are saying here in the
dialogue. So the description is very
good for analysing or for getting a
look how the atmosphere is. If here
would be a different, for example, a
different description, we would get a
different sense of how this dialogue
may be. Also wenn hier zum Beispiel,
ich weiß nicht, Frieden und sehr
laute Geräusche wären, dann wäre das
nicht so friedlich. Also wir würden
einen Sinn bekommen, oh, das ist
nicht friedlich, was ist da los? Aber
jetzt mit dieser Beschreibung können
wir sehen, dass es eine friedliche
Situation ist. Ja, also ein nächstes
Übungsgerät, ein weiteres
Übungsgerät. Es ist auch, wie der
Veränderung der Setting den Mund und
Atmosphäre beeinflusst. Schaut
einfach den Text. Ich werde es alle
auslesen, wie ich es vorher gemacht
habe. Und nur ein oder zwei Antworten
sind genügend. Also, Szene 9. Mit,
okay, es ist von George Bernard Shaw.
Püpp, Marlion. Szene 9. Mit
Dinosaurier, blazend, die Stage ist
überwacht. Bottle's Toast is smashed,
typewriter, ripped out, telephone,
etc. All the debris from previous
scene is now starkly visible in
intense yellow light. The effect
should be like a desert junkyard at
high noon. The coolness of the
preceding scene is totally
obliterated. Austin is seated, a
table in a coffin, shirt open,
pouring with sweat. Hunched over a
writing note. ...
...
So, how does the change of setting
affect the mood and atmosphere? So,
we read the first excerpt and now we
have the second excerpt. Like, how is
the change transmitted? Can you tell
me how is the change of setting
affect the mood and atmosphere? Tell
me. So, write in the chat box maybe.
So.
That's right. So in the first excerpt
they're very relaxed and calm and
everything was peaceful. But now the
change of the setting, like they are
not running, but they are going
somewhere. And everything is very
stressful and it's very uncomfortable
because they're sweating. And here
it's a blazing heat, so it's very,
very hot. And smashed typewriter, a
ripped out telephone, so something is
broken as well. So there's a very
abrupt... Change of settings, change
of mood and atmosphere as well. So
yeah, it's very uncomfortable, the
mood and the atmosphere. Like you
don't feel very good in the setting.
Characters. The characters are a
significant element of every literary
text. With their decisions, dialogue
and action, they determine the course
of action. A character has the
following characteristics. Behavior,
emotions and things. Diese drei
Komponenten sind für Charaktere sehr
üblich. Es ist also wichtig, wenn du
einen Analyse machst, diese drei
Charakteristiken
zu behandeln. Also Verhalten,
Emotionen und Denken. Also, explizite
Charakterisation, also in mehr
Detail. The narrator or another
character describes the character
directly. Therefore following
characteristics are described to the
reader. Outward experience,
appearance, habits, behavior,
attitudes and opinions. So that's an
explicit characterization. So it's in
more detail. The reader gets like
more of what the character looks
like, how the character looks like.
So it gets more details about the
character. Then there is also, so we
have the explicit characterization
and we have the implicit
characterization. The character is
introduced indirectly. The reader has
to analyze given information in order
to define the characteristics of the
character. Information that might be
relevant are thought process,
behavior, speech, way of talking,
appearance, communication with other
characters.
Es ist einfach so, dass der Charakter
indirekt vorgestellt wird. In dem
Buch ist es nicht geschrieben. Ja,
Mr. Johnson hat dunkle Haare, hat
blaue Augen, ist sehr freundlich.
Aber wenn man die Geschichte lesen
kann, bekommt man eine Verständnis
dafür, wie der Charakter sich verhält
oder wie er aussieht. Aber einfach
unbequem. Es wird also nicht
geschrieben, ah, Mr. Johnson ist so
und so, aber es ist implizit. Man
bekommt einen impliziten Sinn, wie
der Charakter aussieht oder wie der
Charakter fühlt, was auch immer.
Konstellation von Charakteren. Die
Konstellation von Charakteren
beschreibt die Beziehung zwischen
Charakteren aus einem literären Text.
We can categorize characters into
groups if some people always stick up
for each other or if we can identify
a leader, a role model.
Every time you describe a character,
they are in a group. So if they stick
in this group. Or we can identify a
leader. So the person who is leading
everything, a role model. Also
possible. Therefore it is important
to consider the relationship.
zwischen den individuellen
Charakteren.
Die Beziehung zwischen den
Charakteren ist wichtig, um die
Verzweiflung von Charakteren zu
bekommen, wie sind die Charaktere mit
einander? Sind sie gute Freunde oder
sind sie mehr als Freunde? Oder sind
sie Feinde? Die Beziehung ist also
sehr wichtig für diese Faktoren. Um
auf die Attitüde zu reflektieren, If
the characters have towards another
character, we can use the following
terms. Affection, dislike,
friendship, rivalry, peaceful
relationship, tense relationship,
distant relationship. Distant
relationship. That's not right here.
It's like this relationship, a very
close relationship. Needs to sound
here. Loyalty and hostility. So these
are like...
different words, how you can describe
a relation, for example.
Development of a character. So,
there's a gradual development. The
development of a character depends on
many factors. It happens in more than
one phase. Then there's the abrupt
change. The character has a sudden
change of heart, often used in short
stories.
In den Geschichten, die Charaktere
verändern sich. Es kann also entweder
ein graduales Entwicklung sein, also
wo man es sehen kann, oder ein
abruptes Verändern. Es wird oft in
Kurzgeschichten genannt. Um den
Entwicklung eines Charakters zu
analysieren, müssen wir die Gründe
für den Veränderung identifizieren,
wie zum Beispiel, was passiert ist
oder warum es passiert ist oder so
weiter. und finden wichtige Quote und
Extrakte, die den Veränderung
signalisieren. Also brauchen wir, um
eine
Quote zu bekommen oder den Extrakt
aus dem Text zu bekommen, der bereits
einen Hinweis
auf den Veränderung aufgibt. So they
put like an important, for example,
question mark or exclamation mark or
whatever. So the story gives us
already a hint of why the person
changes and we need to find it in the
text.
Tasks. So possible tasks concerning
characters can be. Who are the main
characters? How are they presented?
What is the characters function in
the text? Describe the character. Pay
attention to the ...
All these possible tasks can be in
your exam. So, yeah, who are the main
characters? How are they presented?
For example, we just had Lee and
Orson. And now you have to present
them. You have to describe them in
detail. Yeah, and analyze their
behavior, whatever. Another exercise.
Ernst Hemingway, the old man and the
sea. So, the task at the end will
be... He characterized the old man by
using the information that I've given
in the text. Define the relationship
between the two characters and
explain your reasons. He was an old
man who fished alone in a skiff in
the Gulf Stream and he had gone 84
days now without taking a fish. In
the first 40 days the boy had been
with him. But after 40 days without a
fish the boy's parents had told him
that the old man was now definitely
and finally salaud, which is the
worst form of unlove. und der Junge
war in einem anderen Boot, in dem er
drei gute Fische die erste Woche
gefangen hat. Das hat den Junge
gesagt, um den alten Mann jeden Tag
mit seinem Geschenk zu sehen, und er
war immer da, um ihn zu helfen,
entweder die Kuitlein oder die Gaff
und Harpoon zu tragen, und der Seil,
der um die Masse geführt wurde. The
sail was pitched with four floor
sacks and furled it looked like the
flag of permanent defeat. The old man
was thin and gaunt with deep wrinkles
in the back of his neck. The brown
blotches of a benevolent skin cancer
the sun brings from its reflection on
the tropic sea were on his cheeks.
The blotches ran well down the sides
of his face and his hands had the
deep crease. ...
So, now please characterize the old
man by using the information that
I've given in the text. Define the
relationship between the two
characters and explain your reasons.
So, first characterize the old man.
So, can someone tell me, please write
in the box, yeah, some
characteristics of the old man. Can
you tell me? So, some important facts
about the old man. For example, his
behavior, how does he look like? So,
oddward appearance.
Any ideas?
For example, so, we can tell about
the old man that he was odd. So,
then, here.
The old man was thin and gone with
deep wrinkles in the back of his
neck. He
had deep crease scars.
Someone just gave him... Er hat mir
eine Antwort gegeben. Er ist
diszipliniert, wenn er nicht auf
Fisch abgibt. Das ist richtig. Er ist
sehr diszipliniert und er will
wirklich nicht auf Fisch abgeben. Er
ist wirklich dazu, dass er nicht auf
Fisch abgeben will. Das ist ein sehr
wichtiger Faktor für diesen alten
Mann. Das ist die Hauptstelle des
Geschichts, dass der alte Mann, auch
wenn er keinen Fisch bekommt, He is
still fishing. He doesn't stop. Very
good. And now the relationship
between the two characters. So
between the boy and the old man. Can
someone tell me, how is the
relationship? Is it good? Is it bad?
Is it friendly? Is it peaceful? Is it
like, are they enemies? What are
they? Are they friends? Yes,
they are friends and... Someone else
typing.
Okay, so they are friends. And you
can... Man sieht, dass der alte Mann
immer den jungen Jungen mit ihm
mitgenommen hat, um mit ihm angeln zu
gehen. Aber jetzt, als der alte Mann
keine mehr Fische bekommt, verändert
sich der junge Junge in ein anderes
Boot. Und jetzt fühlt sich der junge
Junge ein wenig traurig darüber. Aber
jeden Abend, wenn sie zurückkommen,
hilft der junge Junge dem alten Mann,
die Dinge aus diesem Boot zu
bekommen. So they are more, so they
are friendlier,
like before. So being friendly and
everything, he gives it back, so he
helps him now. Yeah. So the
relationship between them is very
friendly, very peaceful, and they are
helping each other, but in different
ways. It can be like, for example,
emotionally. And so the old man, the
young boy, emotionally, he's there
for him. And he gives them, for
example. hints of how he can do it.
And the young boy now helps him
physically with his power to
transport things out of the boat.
Plot. The plot of a narration
consists of a series of events that
are interconnected. The plot of a
text always contains a starting
situation, opportunities for action,
a change of situation resulting from
an action. In order to analyze the
relevance of events, we have to
identify their symbolic
Also wenn etwas passiert, ist es
chronologisch oder ist es ein
Flashback oder was passiert. Das ist
wichtig, um einen Sinn zu bekommen,
wie die Geschichte geschrieben wird.
Klimax. Der Klimax ist die Part der
Geschichte, wo der höchste Punkt der
Tension erreicht wird. Das ist
normalerweise der Punkt, wo wir den
Hauptproblem der Geschichte befinden,
der dann von einem oder mehr
Hauptcharakteren geschlossen wird.
This often results in a change. For
example, the character constellation
is affected because the relationship
between two characters is
strengthened or an argument is
resolved. That's why the climax is
also often referred to as a turning
point. So a story is mostly built as
there's a rising tension, then
there's a climax. Like the main part
is happening and then there's a
falling tension. That's like... wie
die Geschichte gebaut wird.
Open Ending. Der Ende ist einer der
wichtigsten Teilen der Geschichte.
Wir würden auch erwarten, dass die
Geschichte zu Ende kommt. Das ist
nicht immer der Fall. Manchmal gibt
der Ende der Geschichte keine Lösung,
aber es ist offen. Deshalb könnte die
Geschichte in verschiedene Richtungen
gehen und es ist an den Leser, um den
möglichen Ergebnis zu vorstellen.
Dadurch, Using an open end in a story
motivates the reader to think and to
deal with the subject matter of the
text. Open endings are especially
common in short stories. So, a story
doesn't need an ending, but it also
can have an open ending. And this is
very common for short stories.
So, possible tasks concerning the
plot can be Describe the sequence of
events of the story. How are the
events interconnected?
So all these questions are possible
tasks you can get asked in an exam,
like in an oral exam, whatever, in an
essay.
So, useful phrases for... The
sequence of events. The story is told
chronologically. The story disregards
the chronological order. Later events
are foreshadowed when the story
switches from the present to the past
or the other way around. An event
marks a shift in time. The narrator
uses retro-perspective narration too.
An event anticipates future events.
So useful phrases for the sequence of
events. Useful phrases for the
division of narration. The narrator
tells the story in parts. Five parts,
six parts, whatever. Two parts. The
development rises to a climax when
this and this happens. The story is
organized in major events. Six,
seven, one, two. The story can be
divided into. The story has a
surprise ending. Ending, whatever.
and the event correlates with another
event. So, these are useful phrases
for the composition. That's it. Thank
you for listening. Do you have any
questions? Any questions, please
write in the chat box. If not, yeah,
thank you for listening. You can give
me feedback if you want. Yeah.
So, yes. I'm waiting for you to...
Ask some questions or give me
feedback.
Thank you, Linus. So, at 11 there's
another webinar with me. Another from
the English Abitur Reihe. And at 12
there's another one. So, there's one
at 11 and at 12. So, maybe we see
each other again. And thank you for
listening. So, if that's it, I would
stop the webinar. I would end it. And
I wish you good luck for your future
exams, for your A-Levels, whatever.
We see each other again, hopefully in
one or two hours. We'll see. Thank
you and bye. Have a nice day and good
luck. Ciao.