Hey, Mom. Have you seen my wallet?
Your wallet? Oh, darling, no I
haven't. I can't find my wallet. Did
you look in your school bag? Yes, I
did. But it's not in there. Did you
look in your room? Yes, I did. But
it's not there. Did you look in the
living room on the table? Yes, I did.
And it's not on the table. Well, did
you look in the bathroom? Warum
sollte ich in den Kofferraum schauen?
Na gut, du hast gestern Abend
geschlafen. Vielleicht hast du es da
drin gelegt. Ich werde da hoch
schauen. Nach fünf Minuten. Und? Hast
du deine Wallet gefunden? Du hast
recht. Es war auf dem Konto des
Sinktums in der Kofferraum. Oh, das
ist großartig. Mutter, du bist der
Beste. Danke, Schatz. Ich bin froh,
dass ich dir helfen konnte.