Hi, my name is Jeanne. I am 14 years
old and I live in Paris, the capital
city of France. My school is the
Pierre-Corneille-Lycée, which is in
the city center. I am currently in
the 9th grade, which is similar to
the high school in America. My
favorite school subject is maths,
because I'm very good in calculating.
I get up every day at 7.30 a.m. After
I washed myself and put on some
clothes, I have a little break. Ich
esse normalerweise einen
Schokoladenbrot und trinke ein
bisschen Tee. Danach gehe ich aus dem
Haus. Es ist jetzt 8.30 Uhr. Ich gehe
zur Metro-Station, weil ich den
Trainingsweg nehmen muss. Das dauert
normalerweise 15 Minuten, damit ich
um 8.45 Uhr an meiner Schule komme.
15 Minuten bevor meine Lektionen
beginnen. An Tüsdagen, zum Beispiel,
beginnt mein Schulabschluss mit zwei
Stunden Sport, wo wir jetzt Fußball
spielen. I have a lot of fun there
because I can play with all my
friends. Sometimes we also play
against our neighbor class. The last
time we won 4-3. After a short break,
I go to the next class with my
friends, Mathematics. So far, Tuesday
seems to be the best day. Our classes
normally take 60 minutes per subject.
Sometimes I think that it's a bit too
long because I can't focus that long.
But... Apart from that, I am having a
lot of fun and our teachers are very
nice to us. For example, we don't
have a classic blackboard in our
classroom. My school provides each
pupil with a tablet, where we all
have our books downloaded, so I don't
have to carry all these heavy books
with me the whole time. Also, we have
to do our homework on the tablet too.
There's a cloud where my teachers
upload some exercises every week,
which we have to upload at the end.
Die Endzeit der Woche. Dann hätte ich
mehr Zeit, mit meinen Freunden mit
dem Motorrad zu fahren, zum Beispiel.