Hast du bemerkt, wie der Mayor die
neue Transportnetze hier geplant hat?
Nicht wirklich. Was wurde erneut
erneut? Our mayor announced in an
interview yesterday that he's
planning to reduce the speed in the
city center and that e-scooters are
no longer allowed to be used on the
pedestrian paths. With what
justification would he like to
enforce these measures? Lately there
have been more and more accidents
caused by fast-paced motorists. Cars
are also the main contributor to
global warming and air pollution.
They are taking up too much space and
they put cyclists at risk. What is
the current speed limit in... You are
currently allowed to drive 50 km per
hour in the city center. The mayor
plans to reduce the speed by 20 km
per hour. Does that mean that you can
then only drive 30 km per hour in the
car? Yes, it does. I think that's a
good idea. What do you think? In my
opinion, that's going too far. It'll
mean that you need a lot more time to
get to your destination. Also, I
doubt that cars are contributing that
much to global warming. What do you
think? Was ist mehr für die globale
Wärme? Na, zum Beispiel die
Produktion von Konkret oder outdaten
Heizungssystemen. Das ist vielleicht
wahr, aber ich denke, dass Gebäude
zum Beispiel nicht so einfach
entfernt werden können. Ich denke,
die Forschung ist noch nicht in
dieser Aree da. Stattdessen kann man
versuchen, das Stadtzentrum grüner
und freundlicher zu machen, indem man
mehr auf elektrische Autos verlangt,
building wider bike paths and more
green spaces overall. That's true. I
also noticed that almost all of the
cars on the street I live on are
parked permanently. I have a feeling
that people don't use their cars
because they don't want to give up
their parking space on their
doorstep. I agree. And now imagine
how this space could be used for
other purposes. There would be more
space to plant trees, people could
move more freely on the sidewalk.
Such concepts... Ich habe viel Arbeit
in Metropolisen wie Amsterdam und
Wien. Nicht nur macht man gut für die
Umwelt, aber die Menschen sind auch
glücklicher. Aber wie sollen schwere
Läden transportiert werden? Mehr und
mehr Teilen der Stadt bieten die
Möglichkeit, Kargo-Bikes gratis zu
rentieren. Außerdem eröffnen sich
jetzt viele Orte zu deinem Haus, ohne
Anreize. Ich wusste das wirklich
nicht. Ich werde dir später einen
Link schicken.