You will listen to two different
advertisements. Answer the questions
about these. Advertisement 1. You are
looking for serious news and the
meaning behind the facts? Do not look
further. We have the perfect solution
for you. We will inform you about
everything that you would like to
know. For example, sports, TV series,
political decisions, local
information about New York and
changes. All around the world. Our
experienced and objective columnists
always receive the information at
first and they will deliver them
seriously as well as informative to
you at the very next day. The Daily
World Press appears every day in
every country and is available at
bookshops, railway stations and
online under www.dailyworld.org. Get
your copy today.
Advertisement 2
Untertitelung des ZDF für funk, 2017
mind. You can contact your Realizing
Sun studio on the internet or on www
.realizing.com or you can call us at
345133 We look forward to seeing you
soon.