Hallo, mein Name ist Lisa aus
Großbritannien. Ich bin 15 Jahre alt
und sehr interessiert in Sport. Mein
Lieblingssport ist Cricket, der sehr
populär ist im UK, aber auch in
Indien. Cricket ist ein Spiel mit
zwei Gruppen, den Beatern und den
Bowlern. Es sind 11 Spieler in jedem
Team. Manchmal sind es auch 12
Spieler. Wenn jemand getötet wird
während des Spiels, er oder sie.
could substitute the injured. One
inning, this is what a round of
cricket is called, is one hour and
fifteen minutes long. In this time,
the goal is nearly the same as in
baseball. A player of the beaters is
called batter. He or she has to beat
the ball and one of his or hers other
teammates has to run to the wicket of
the fielding team and back again to
score one point for his team. The
bowlers must try to get the batter
before his teammate has the
opportunity to run. The goal for them
is to catch the ball before the
batter arrives from the wicket. If
the fielding team can catch the ball,
the batter is out and has to be
substituted by one of his teammates.
After 1 hour and 15 minutes, the
teams switch their positions. The
batter team becomes the bowler team
and The winner is the team which
scored the most runs in. My favorite
position in the game is the batter
position. I am very good at it and my
team wins very often. Maybe you would
like to try it as well.