Hey, what is your hobby? My favorite
hobby is playing tennis. That's
interesting. What do you need for
tennis? Well, you need a tennis court
where you can play. And you need a
tennis racket, a tennis ball and
somebody to play with as well. Can I
join you one day? Of course, that
would be awesome. I can show you how
to play. I'm looking forward to it.
Me too. Alex, do you have a hobby? I
play ice hockey in a team. Wow, that
sounds fun. How often do you play ice
hockey? I play ice hockey twice a
week. Do you have a favorite ice
hockey team? I'm a huge fan of the
Chicago Blackhawks. They're the best.
Oh, I know this team. I watched them
play last night. I watched the game
too. Did you like it? Yes, they
played pretty well. That's why
they're the best.