Die Feindin Marilyn Monroe war eine
berühmte Schauspielerin, Sängerin und
Modellin. Sie wurde in Los Angeles
geboren, ein Staat in Kalifornien, in
den USA, 1926. Ihr echter Name war
Norma Jean Mortensen. Normas Kindheit
war sehr schwierig. Seine Mutter
Gladys hatte eine mentale Krankheit
und konnte nicht ihre Tochter
kümmern. Sein Vater Charles verlor
Gladys, als sie krank wurde.
Therefore Norma was placed with
foster parents and spent her
childhood in and out of foster home
until she turned 16. At this age she
married the man James Doherty, who
was a friend of hers and lived close
by. When James joined the military,
Norma started working as a model. In
1945 she signed in with the agency
Blue Book Model and colored her hair
blonde. Von diesem Moment an begann
sie in verschiedenen Magazinen und
Covers zu erscheinen. Sie hat die
Geld, die sie mit ihrem Job verdient
hat, auf Bücher, Literaturkursen und
auf einem Aktivismuskurs gespart.
Während dieses Kurses hat sie Ben
Lyon getroffen, der ihr einen
Kontrakt als Aktressin erhielt. Das
war der Zeitpunkt, als Norma ihren
Namen in den Stagenamen Marilyn
Monroe verändert hat. 1947 divorced
she James and started working as an
actress full time. From this moment
on she was seen in different roles in
multiple films and became a famous
star. Marilyn was a very attractive
woman and for this reason she got a
lot of attention from men. The most
iconic photo of Marilyn is her
standing over a sidewalk with her
skirt blowing up. Because she was
tired of dumb blonde roles and
looking for more dramatic roles, she
moved to New York. There she found a
new director and finally got serious
roles. In 1956 she met Arthur Miller,
who turned out to be the love of her
life. They got married the same year
at a small wedding. Finally, Marilyn
found the happiness she was looking
for since her childhood.
Unfortunately, it turned out that
Arthur was not as happy with the
marriage and Marilyn was heartbroken.
They kept the marriage together but
Marilyn started psychotherapy and
began taking sleeping pills and
drinking alcohol to sleep. She was
not able to focus on her career
anymore and was fired from several
projects because she was always late
and difficult to work with. When
Arthur fell in love with another
woman, they got divorced. In May
1962, drei Monate bevor sie gestorben
war, sang sie Happy Birthday to
President John F. Kennedy at a
Democratic Fundraiser at the Madison
Square Garden. This performance was
one of her last. On August 5, 1962,
she was discovered in her home with
an overdose of sleeping pills. The
circumstances of her death are still
unclear.