Lisa from Germany is with her family
in London for the holidays. They've
just finished a tour to Big Ben and
have got lost on their way back to
the hotel. So they ask a pedestrian
for the way. Excuse me, sir. Can I
ask you for some help? Yeah, sure. I
hope that I can help you. What do you
need? We're looking for our hotel,
the Central Inn. Can you tell us how
to get there? Unfortunately, I
haven't heard of that hotel. The name
of the street is Royal Avenue. Maybe
you know it. Ah, yes, I know this
street. A friend of mine lives there.
Do you also know the number? Because
the street is quite long. Yes, of
course. The hotel has number 311.
Okay, great. Yes, I think I know
where that is. Because my friend
lives in number 322. How do you want
to get there? I know a bus that goes
there, as well as the underground. On
our way to the city center, Wir haben
den Untergrund getragen, aber wenn es
einfacher ist, können wir auch den
Bus zurücknehmen. Ich denke, dass das
Untergrund das schnellste Weg ist, um
da zu kommen. Geh einfach auf die
Station Kings Cross und nimm die rote
Linie. Dann hast du nur fünf Stoppe,
bis du dein Destination bekommst.
Gut, und in welcher Richtung müssen
wir die rote Linie nehmen? Nimm die
rote Linie, die nach dem Flughafen
geht. Es wird auf dem Trainingsrad
geschrieben. Dann gehst du in die
richtige Richtung. Okay, ich werde
das erinnern. Und die Station, an der
wir die Untergrund-Route verlassen
müssen, ist Piccadilly Circus,
richtig? Das ist richtig. Und dein
Hotel wird nicht weit weg sein.
Danke. Und könntest du uns auch
sagen, wo die Station Kings Cross
ist? Wir wissen es leider nicht, weil
wir eine andere Runde hier in unseren
Weg genommen haben. Das wäre schön.
Nice. Sure, I can tell you the way.
You just need to go across the big
junction near the roundabout. Then go
straight ahead. At the traffic
lights, turn right. Then you're
there. Perfect. I'll keep the
directions in mind. Thank you so much
for your help and your time. That was
very friendly of you. We wish you a
nice day. You're more than welcome. I
hope you enjoy the time here in
London. Have a nice day. Yes, we like
it a lot here. Thank you. The same to
you. Bye. Goodbye.