Sophia would like to try a new sport,
but does not know which one is right
for her. Emre, do you know team
sports? Let me think. Well, I play
football in a team, and my friends
play basketball in a team. So, here
you go. Football and basketball are
team sports. Right. I would like to
try a new sport, but I don't know
which one is right for me. What about
playing volleyball? Hmm, I tried it.
It's not for me. Was ist mit
Basketball? Hm, ich habe es versucht.
Ich kann nicht auf den Basket treten.
Was ist mit Fußball? Ich bin nicht so
schnell im Rennen. Okay, lass mich
sehen. Was ist mit Tennis? Ich habe
es versucht. Ich kann nicht auf den
Ball treten mit einem Tennis-Racket.
Na, was ist mit Tanzen? Oh, ich habe
nie über Tanzen gedacht. Es gibt eine
Tanzklasse jeden Weihnachtsabend um 5
Uhr. Ich werde es versuchen. Danke
für deine Hilfe. Du bist willkommen.