Jill ist auf dem Weg zu ihrer ersten
Fußball-Praktik. Auf dem Fußball-Feld
sind einige ihrer neuen Teamleute und
ihr neuer Fußball-Coach. Sie warten
auf sie. Willkommen! Hallo! Mein Name
ist Stefan Anders und ich bin der
Coach. Ich leite dieses Team. Würdest
du dich zu deinem neuen Team
vorstellen? Klar! Mein Name ist Jill
Gregorian. I am 12 years old and I
live around the corner, on Sandford
Street, next to the Kebab House. I
moved two years ago from Germany. I
hope you like Great Britain. Yes, I
do. Why did you choose this soccer
team? I love soccer and I live in
this area. I thought I should give it
a try. Great. So, have you ever
played soccer before? Well, I
sometimes played soccer with my
younger brother in our backyard. But
most... Most of the time I watched
soccer on TV. Okay, we will see. How
do you feel? Are you excited? I am
really excited and I can't wait to
play. Great. Let's go, girls.