The Outback in Australia is a huge
region, which covers most of
Australia. It's made up of 10 deserts
and also subtropical savannah and the
largest temperate woodland on earth.
Let's start our little Outback tour
with Uluru, also known as Ayers Rock.
It's a large sandstone rock, higher
than the Eiffel Tower. It's 348
meters tall. Uluru is one of
Australia's most recognizable
natural... Landmarks and has been a
tourist attraction since 1930. In the
Outback you can drive on the world's
longest straight road. It's 146.6
kilometers long without a bend.
There's also the world's longest
fence, which was built in 1885. It's
5,614 kilometers long. Only the Great
Wall of China is longer. Most people
think that the Outback Outback is a
dry desert, but it rains a lot there.
Some years there is no rain, but in
others there are floods. The
temperatures in the central deserts
can easily reach 50 degrees in the
summer. In winter it's very cold,
with minus 10 degrees. One of the
most seen animals in the Outback is
the camel. There are over one million
roaming Australia. It's the largest
number of purebred camels in the
world. Der Outback hat viele
verschiedene Namen. Zum Beispiel der
Never Never und der Back of Beyond.
Es ist 5,3 Millionen Quadratkilometer
groß und fast 22-mal größer als die
UK. Und der Outback ist einer der
besten Plätze im Weltraum für
Stargazing.