Welcome to our webinar on the topic
of usage of a dictionary. Let's take
a look at dictionaries. If you're
learning a foreign language, a
dictionary will be an invaluable
tool. There's no easier way to answer
a question regarding vocabulary. You
don't have to depend on another
person, you can just look it up.
Especially convenient are
dictionaries that you can use online,
as they are always accessible and you
can just enter them. die Wörter, die
du wirklich schnell suchst. Und du
musst nicht einen schweren Diktator
mit dir tragen. Du kannst nur dein
Smartphone oder Computer benutzen.
Aber du solltest auch wissen, welches
Diktator dir die Informationen, die
du eigentlich brauchst, gibt und
natürlich, wie du sie benutzt.
Diktatorien sind Eingänge, die mit
einem Hörwort beginnen. Diese
Eingänge sind sind alphabetisch
verordnet, um es einfacher zu finden.
Nach jedem Hauptwort findet man
weitere Informationen, zum Beispiel
die Übersetzung und die Prononziation
des entsprechenden Wortes. Diese
Informationen können in der
Information über das Hauptwort und in
der Information über die Definition
des Hauptwortes geklassifiziert
werden. Jeder Diktator hat sein
eigenes System von Symbolen und
Abbrevungen. These are defined in the
key, which you can find on the first
page of the dictionary.
So we can see here how information is
classified between headword and
definition. Relating information on
the headword, we can find information
on the pronunciation, auf die
Grammatik, auf die Bedingungen und
die Derivative und auf die Synonyme,
die den gleichen Sinn wie das
Hauptwort enthalten. Die Definition
des Hauptwortes, Sie können den Sinn
des Wortes finden, wie es in Idiomen
oder phrasalen Verben verbunden ist,
und Sie können Beispiele für seine
Benutzung finden.
a couple of various kinds of
dictionaries you should be aware of.
First of all, the most common known
bilingual dictionary, which is a
dictionary that shows the words of a
language translated into another
language. For example, from English
into German or vice versa. Then there
are monolingual dictionaries. These
explain a word in the same language.
A special kind of these are
monolingual learners dictionaries,
which are especially designed for
learners of a language. Last but not
least, there are collocations
dictionaries. These provide common
word combinations. So let's start
with bilingual dictionaries.
Bilinguale Dictionaries sind
besonders wichtig für Beginner. Sie
bieten eine Übersetzung eines Wortes
zu einer anderen Sprache, sowie
Informationen über Pronunziation,
Wortklasse und meistens auch
Beispiele. Aber ihr müsst vorsichtig
sein. Auch wenn ihr die Übersetzung
des Wortes finden wollt, kann es
nicht für den bestimmten Kontext
aussehen. Schauen wir uns das Wort
Groß an. Ein bilinguales Dictionary
wird euch sagen, dass Groß... can be
translated with big, great, high,
large and tall. But you cannot use
every word in the same context. For
example, if you want to say ein
großes Gebäude, you can use high and
tall. But you cannot use great or
large, as that would be incorrect in
the English language. While bilingual
dictionaries are especially in the
beginning, you should try to use a
monolingual or a learner's dictionary
later on, as they might help you in
the long go. We got an example for an
entry
in a bilingual dictionary. We got the
word bold, the pronunciation in
British and American English. What
word class it belongs to, it's an
adjective. And then the meaning. The
first translation, mutig or
unerschrocken. An example, to take a
bold step. And the translation of the
example. Dann noch ein anderes
Wortbeispiel und ein Beispiel und die
Übersetzung des Beispiels. Und dann
haben wir eine Phrase. Ein Beispiel
einer Phrase. As bold as brass, das
ist ein Idiom und würde in der Regel
mit Frech wie Oskar in Deutsch
übersetzt werden. As there is always
the difficulty with idioms and
different languages.
Monolingual dictionaries are
important for your learning process.
They can help you to become a more
proficient speaker of the English
language. A monolingual dictionary
might be more difficult to use
compared to a bilingual dictionary,
as you will not see a direct
translation for the word in your
native language. But a monolingual
dictionary will not only describe
the... different meanings of a word.
Often there is more than one meaning
for a word. It will also provide you
with more comprehensive information
about the language that you're
learning. Especially important for
learners are monolingual learners
dictionaries, which we will see
later. So here we got an example of
monolingual dictionary. We got our
head word business. See the
pronunciation britisch und
amerikanisch und welcher Wörterklasse
sie gehört. Danach können wir alle
verschiedenen Bedeutungen des
Geschäfts finden. Und weil es
monolingual ist, wird immer erklärt,
welches Bedeutung das Geschäft hat.
In diesem Fall. Also zum Beispiel für
den ersten Jahrhundert ist das
Geschäft die Aktivität of making,
buying or selling things for money,
commerce or trade. Another meaning of
business would be a company or a shop
is a business. Then we get a thing
that is somebody's concern, a duty or
a task. Like you would say, that is
my business or it is not your
business. So we got a lot of
different meanings, which are always
explained in in der gleichen Sprache,
was sehr hilfreich macht, um die
verschiedenen Bedeutungen zu
verstehen, als nur eine einzigartige
Übersetzung.
Lernende Diktionen sind besonders für
Menschen, die im Prozess der Lernung
einer Sprache sind, gesteuert.
Diktionen sollten nicht nur eine
Liste von isolierten Worten und deren
Bedeutungen von Übersetzungen
enthalten. Deshalb findet man in
einer Lernenden Diktion nicht nur die
verschiedenen Bedeutungen of a word,
but also additional information, for
example the grammatical structure,
that help you to use the word in the
correct way and to put it in the
appropriate context. Therefore it is
important that you not just look at
the first definition of meaning.
Words can be polysemous and have
several different meanings, just as
we've seen in business. Another
example is to buy. One meaning is to
obtain something by paying money for
it. That's if we buy something in a
shop. The second meaning is informal.
To believe that something is true.
Especially something that is not very
likely. So if someone is telling me
something and I believe it, I could
also say I'm buying it.
Die Oxford Learners Dictionaries sind
eine vertragliche Sorge, die Ihnen
helfen kann, in jeder Phase Ihres
Sprachlernprozesses zu helfen. Sie
können sie sogar online anbieten und
mit der Suche-Aktion schnell
Informationen über jede Worte, die
Sie brauchen, finden. Folgt einfach
der Anzeige, die wir hier belegt
haben. Die
Informationen, die Sie finden können,
sind in der Detail und wertvoll. Sie
finden jede mögliche Weise, wie eine
Worte verstanden und benutzt werden
kann. Many examples and useful
phrases are available. We got the
example of our word buy here. So our
first meaning would be buy with
money. So the meaning would be to
obtain something by paying money for
it. Like buy something, buy something
from somebody, buy somebody
something. So here are some.
grammatische Strukturen, die man mit
buy-in benutzen kann. Man sieht auch
das Gegenteil der Wörter, was sell
ist. Das zweite Wichtigste wäre,
etwas Geld zu kaufen, um genug zu
bezahlen, wie er seinen Kindern die
beste Bildung gab, die Geld kaufen
kann. Ein
weiteres Wichtigste wäre, jemanden zu
kaufen, um jemanden zu überzeugen,
etwas something dishonest in return
for money. So buy is here used the
same way as bribe is. That's why you
see the synonym bribe entry.
Collocations describe how we can
combine words so that they sound
natural in a given context.
Collocations usually are pairs of
words like a verb and a noun for find
information or an adjective in a
noun, as in blue water, an adverb and
a noun, as in highly significant, or
a noun and a preposition, like
information concerning. Sometimes it
is difficult to determine which verb,
adjective, adverb or preposition we
can combine with the word we want to
use. Let's have a look at the
following examples. Wir haben eine
Bezeichnung wie hohe Temperatur, die
korrekt ist. Aber wenn wir uns die
Übersetzungen des Wortes Groß
anschauen, wurde auch gesagt, dass
groß eine andere Übersetzung ist.
Aber wir können nicht groß in
Kombination mit Temperatur verwenden,
weil groß ist nicht Sinnvoll. So this
would be an incorrect collocation.
The same goes for have an experience
as a correct collocation compared to
do or make an experience. Or
disappointed by compared to
disappointed from.
To solve these problems we use
collocation dictionaries. Especially
if you have to write your own text in
the English language, you will find
yourself in a position. where you
have to decide on word collocations.
One possibility is to just search for
information in the Internet. You will
find a lot of suggestions, but you
have to make sure that the source
you're dealing with is reliable.
Therefore it's easier to look up the
information you need in a collocation
dictionary. These are especially
designed for the purpose of finding
possible word combinations that you
can use in your particular context.
Die Diktionäre der Kollocation zeigen
dir, welche Verben, Adjektive,
Adverbien, Präpositionen und Launen
du mit einem Wort nutzen kannst. Sie
differenzieren auch zwischen den
verschiedenen Bedeutungen eines
Wortes, da es Unterschiede gibt und
die Kombinationen, die du nutzen
kannst. Die Oxford Collocation
Diktionäre ist eine verantwortliche
Sorge. Die Vorteile sind, dass sie
auch eine Software für ihre
Diktionäre bieten, die du auf deinem
Computer installieren kannst. So you
do not only get a printed version,
but you also have the opportunity to
use the collocation dictionary on
your computer. That makes it easier
to look up stuff, because you can
just use the search option. You will
find the possible collocations, as
well as information about the meaning
and examples. We got an example here.
So the word we looked up is
assignment. We get our first meaning,
which is task, and are provided with
a list of adjectives we can use with
assignment, like a special
assignment, an important assignment,
a photographic assignment. Next, we
get verbs that are commonly used in
combination with assignment, like
accept or take on, and get provided
with examples where the word is used,
like, why did you take on this
assignment if you're so busy? Or, as
in the case of refuse, if you refuse
this assignment, you risk losing your
job. Next, we are given prepositions
that we can use with assignment,
like, on assignment, the photographer
is on assignment in China at the
moment. For the next meeting, of
assignment, which is also a piece of
school or college work, we get
different adjectives, because
compared to a task, a piece of school
work would make much more sense as a
homework assignment, a class
assignment or a written assignment.
Here we also find different verbs
that can be used to combine with
assignment, like Like give, as in the
teacher gave us an assignment on
pollution. Write an assignment.
Finish an assignment. Or hand in, as
in the students handed in their
assignments. Also in preposition we
find a different combination. As in
an assignment on modern lifestyle. So
assignment on. Instead of on
assignment, as in a task. Die meisten
Lehrer werden euch ermutigen, einen
Diktionär zu verwenden, besonders
einen Monolingual Learner Diktionär.
Sie sollten einen Lehrer fragen,
welchen Diktionär Sie verwendet
werden können und vielleicht sogar
eine Befehlung fragen, wenn Sie nicht
sicher sind, welchen zu bekommen, da
es viele verschiedene Diktionäre
gibt. Aber Sie müssen vorsichtig
sein, weil es so nützlich wie ein
Diktionär sein könnte. Do not make
the mistake of using it too much in
situations where you only have a
limited amount of time. For example
on an exam. You won't have time to
look up every single word and find
the perfect phrase. Try to think of a
solution for yourself first. Maybe
you can just rephrase an idea without
using the exact word. Only use the
dictionary if it is really necessary
when you are taking an exam.
Und damit sind wir am Ende unseres
Webinars. Ich möchte euch bedanken
für euer Aufmerksamkeit und hoffe,
dass ihr einen schönen Tag habt.