Welcome to our webinar on the topic
of analyzing scientific texts. So
before analyzing a scientific text,
let's take a look what scientific
texts actually are. Scientific texts
and also historical texts,
technological texts, accounts or
reports are directed at a
professional audience or a reader
that is interested in in the subject
matter. So typical characteristics of
scientific texts are an expository
structure, a main purpose that is
developed, although also additional
ideas and thoughts might be included
in the text. The usage of a
professional terminology, a formal
and objective language, complex
sentences and abundant evidence. also
Quoten aus anderen wissenschaftlichen
Texten, Grafen und Figuren, um die
Argumente des Autors zu unterstützen.
Wissenschaftliche Texte benutzen
meistens fünf Strukturen.
Generalisierung, also die Hauptideen
sind gestaltet oder durch Erklärungen
oder Beispiele klargestellt.
Enumeration, also die Liste von
Fakten für ein Thema. Sequence, which
means they list up a series of events
or steps that are connected.
Classification, meaning a grouping of
items into classes. And comparison or
contrast, a relationship between two
or more subjects is established and
or analyzed.
Now how can we identify claims?
Claims are the basis for any
argument. Whenever we want to support
our position, we need claims to be
convincing. These claims can be
categorized into claims of fact or
definition, comparison, cause, value
and policy. And all of these claims
need to be supported by reliable
sources. So let's start with claims
of fact. Claims of Fact answer the
following questions. Did it happen?
Is it true? Does it exist? Or is it a
fact? They can be supported by facts,
inductive reasoning, like citing
examples and then drawing
conclusions, by analogies, signs and
expert opinions. Claims of Fact can
be organized in chronological order.
Topical Order, depending on the
author's wishes. Usually they are one
of the first claims to be made in an
argument.
Claims of definition answer the
following questions. How should it be
classified? What is it? What is it
like? How should it be interpreted?
How does the meaning change in a in
einem spezifischen Kontext. Sie
können von vertraglichen Sourcen,
Autoritäten und Analogen unterstützt
werden. Begriffe der Definition sind
benutzt, um zu vergleichen und
Kontrast zu machen, aber auch um
Gründe für die Kontroverse zu geben,
also zu erklären, warum man eine
alternative Sicht akzeptieren sollte.
Sie können auch in einer topischen
Art umgesetzt werden.
Begriffe von Grundsätzen beantworten
die folgenden Fragen. What is the
cause? Where did it come from? What
are the effects? What did happen?
Which results can be expected short
and long term?
They can be supported by factual
data, analogies, statistics, signs of
certain causes, induction and
deduction. So claims of cause are
claims.
auf die Konsequenzen selbst, also
welche Auswirkungen hat eine
Konsequenz und was genau passiert
ist, zum Beispiel in einem
Experiment.
Begriffe von Wert beantworten die
folgenden Fragen. Ist es gut oder
schlecht? Wie schlecht oder wie gut
ist es? Was ist es wert? Ist es moral
oder immoral? Welche Leute denken es
so? Und was ist wert? What values of
criteria are recommended to determine
the goodness, badness of it? Do my
values differ from other people's
values? They can be supported by
motivational appeals, analogies,
appeals to value, quotation from
authorities, induction, signs and
definitions.
Claims of policy answer the...
folgende Fragen. Wie sollten wir
umgehen? Was sollen wir tun? Wie
sollten die Policien in der Zukunft
verändern? Wie kann ein Problem
geschlossen werden? Welcher Kurs der
Aktion ist notwendig, um ein Problem
zu lösen? Wie Sie schon sehen,
fokussieren sich die Begriffe der
Politik meistens auf die Zukunft.
Diese können von Daten, Statistiken,
Definitionen, moralischen und
gemeinsamen Sinn Motivationale
Begriffe, Argumente von Autoritäten,
Ausgaben und literäre Analogen. Da
Argumente ein Teil von
wissenschaftlichen Texten sind, sind
Begriffe für ihre Struktur wichtig.
Normalerweise gibt es nicht nur einen
bestimmten Begriff in einem Text. Es
ist möglich, dass zwei oder mehr
verschiedene Begriffe gefunden werden
können. Es ist immer nützlich, um die
größte, vorausschreitende Begriffe zu
identifizieren, which supports the
main purpose of the argument. You
should also know how the claim is
supported, like if it's by analogies
or an expert opinion, and if the
author used a certain strategy to
organize the argument.
An essay is a special form of
scientific text. The aim of an essay
is not to report with scientific
accuracy. The focus of an essay is to
deal with the subject matter from the
viewpoint in a structured manner. So,
an essay is not supposed to convince
a reader.
The author works around a leading
question. An essay is supposed to be
short, but sophisticated and
subjective. Usually, you will not
find new insights or empirical
findings, but an already existing
Essays can be expository or
argumentative and they want to give
the reader something to think about.
In order to analyze a scientific
text, here are some of the most
common tasks. Analyze the structural
elements of the following text. How
is the subject matter presented? What
is the author's attitude towards the
subject? How is the reader influenced
by the structure of the text?
Consider the different kinds of
structures and claims that are
commonly used in scientific texts.
Connect these two concepts and
analyze the author's intentions and
the effects that are caused by the
structural elements and organization.
It is important that you do not have
to interpret the scientific text.
These are supposed to inform and
deliver facts. Sie sollten sich auf
die Struktur und die Organisation
konzentrieren. Schauen Sie, welche
Art von Sourcen ein Autor benutzt
hat, nicht, welche Art von Worten er
dafür benutzt hat.
Also am Ende haben wir hier ein
Übungsprozess. hier. You're supposed
to take a look at Francesco
Alberoni's text, Stardom and
Charisma, and analyze how the issue
of the text is presented. Identify
structural elements that are used to
emphasize the message of the text.
And
with that, we're at the end of our
webinar. I want to thank you for your
attention and hope you have an Nice
day!