So, hello and welcome to the webinar
today in English language variants,
rhetorical devices. My name is
Sarah Fischer, I'm glad
you're here and
first of all I would ask you to
write in the chat if you
can see the presentation.
Okay, very good.
Good, okay. Right, I've had
a few messages privately now,
but it's fine if you
can see it. Right, I don't know if you'
ve ever been to one of my webinars
. Basically
, I give the presentation and
at the end you still have time for
questions if you want me to explain
something again
, if something has remained unclear.
Right, then we'll start. That's
it . Stylistic devices means
creative devices. Exactly, and the
primary webinar will now be in
English. So, stylistic
devices. Literature and words are
used to
give an excellent sense, idea or feeling.
Figurative language is important to
make words unique and interesting. That
makes sense, right? And
knowledge of stylistic devices is
important to
identify their meaning and effect on the
text . Often stylistic devices give
recommendations, clarity or
freshness of expression. The author
of the text mainly uses stylistic
devices to create a certain effect or
to focus the reader's attention on a
desired issue.
We start with the Anaphora of Deutsch
die Anaphora. Anaphora describes
overt repetition at the beginning of
a sentence in order to give emphasis
to them. For example, In every cry of
every man, in every infant's cry of
fear, in every voice, in every bed.
Quite clear, like every start is
same, so there is a repetition at the
beginning of sentences, and it
emphasizes them. Emphasizes, I'm
sorry. That is an F-O-R-A, you
probably know that from German as
well. The obliteration describes the
repeated sound of the first consonant
in a series of words. Therefore the
sentence is rhythmized and
emphasized. For example, a lazy lying
lion. Then there is allusion. That is
a reference to a character, a myth,
an event, literary work or work of
art. And often it's used to explain a
situation with a well-known
situation. Like an example. I feel
like I'm going down. down the rabbit
hole. It does refer to Alice and One
Chain Wonderland. So it explains the
situation where the lyrical eye, for
example, is in. And everybody knows,
okay, like down the rabbit hole, it
feels like excited or stuff. Yeah,
that is allusion.
Ambiguity, so mehrdeutschkeit,
describes a word, a symbol or a
circumstance that has plural meaning.
and it's often used to humorize the
situation. For example, the sauce is
too hot. It got different meanings.
For example, it can be too strongly
heated or it's very spicy. So you
don't know what exactly is meant.
Maybe kind of self-explanatory,
right? So antithesis or contrast,
also antithesis, emphasizes the
contrast between two things. Things
or characters, for example, love
is an ideal thing, relationship is
a real thing. A confusion of the
real with the ideal is never
indispensable. You can see here
quite obviously that
the first lot is ideal and then
on the other hand as a contrast
or as an entity the relationship is
a real thing. So it separates
love and relationship. Yes, so the
climax, you probably know that
from German or from Latin.
The climax describes the change
in a text where the tension or the
value level is slowly increased. For
example, as you
can see here in the formation, there is a
rising
tension, then there is the climax,
the highest point, and then there
is the tension. For example, he
heard a noise. He got out of
bed and walked into the room. When he
walked down the stairs, he saw a
shadow. Suddenly, like there is
rising tension, right? Yeah, that is
climax. For example, yeah, in general
it could also like be, like with
adjective, for example, good, well,
best. Yeah, that would also be a
climax. Anticlimax is the opposite of
a climax. and describes the transition
from an important problem to a
less important problem.
So it can also refer to the tension that
is
discovered. So not an
ascendancy, as it is for Karmix
, but a discovery. For
example, when a plot
becomes very interesting and then
something
crazy or bad happens. So
there is a rising tension, then
comes Karmix and then there is
anti-climax. So the lowest point.
He has seen the ravages of war. He
has known natural catastrophes. He
has been to single bars. Right? It's
quite boring. Who cares, right? So
there's anticlimax. The ellipsis. So
ellipse describes the omission of a
word or phrase without a change in
the meaning. So this can lead to a
more causal or colloquial tone. This
is always used in speech,
but
not so often in written language . He
ordered two drinks and his friend
won. You would say that, but
you can say that something
is missed if you want. The anumeration,
Auszählung, in German it can also
be inumeration. and that is used
for listing details or to mention
words and phrases step by step. They
can clarify a topic and make it
understandable for the reader and it
also helps to avoid ambiguity. So you
remember ambiguity. For example,
I remember the neck curls, limp and
damp as tendrils, and her quick look,
a sightlong picarous smile, and how,
once startled into talk, The light
syllables leaped for her, and she
balanced in the delight of her
thoughts. Here. There were quite a
lot of enumeration. Here, for listing
details, it clarifies the talking.
The euphemism, so euphemismus in
German, replaces words and phrases
which are impolite or harsh with
polite, indirect expressions. For
example, he's a special child.
instead of he's disabled or learning
challenged or he's got a lot of
temperature, for example. Maybe you
know it in German. It's the typical
example of saying entschlafen instead
of sterben. So, yeah, it's an
embellishment. Or a
positive paraphrase, I say,
of a possible negative. So,
the exclamation or interjections.
Also exclamation. These are short
expressions to show feelings of
surprise or joy or something. For
example, oops or cool or wow.
Whatever. The hyperbole, so hyperbole
in German, is an obvious and often
unreal exaggeration of a statement to
emphasize a point of view. Like you
always use it in your own colloquial
speech, so that is quite often. often
used stylistic device. For example, I
had to wait in the station for 10
days in eternity.
So, inversion describes a literary
technique in which the normal order
of words is reversed. So, often
inversions are used to achieve an
effect of an emphasis. For example,
here by the rose tree They planted
wands of lavender party in Italian
bronze. So, you see, it's not the
normal order of words. It's often
used in poems and then you can
like... Normally, a special word is
emphasized and then you can analyze
that one.
Irony, these are when words are used
in a way that their intended meaning
differs from the actual meaning. This
figure of speech illustrates the
difference between appearance and
reality. We can differentiate between
verbal and situational irony. Verbal
irony is using words to express
something different from the literal
meaning. For example, my teacher is
as kind-hearted as a wolf. You say
it's ironic. And the situational
irony, the result is different from
the expectation. So, the reader
expects something to happen,
but then something that
means the whole story. For example, in The
Wizard of
Oz. The main character is looking for the
Wizard to come back. But
ironically, she can get herself
back without knowing it. That
's irony too. Probably how
we usually
say it in Germany. We will probably talk
about
the verbal ironies. A
metaphor is a stylistic device that
expresses an implicit, hidden or
implied comparison between two
things. And these things are usually
unrelated, but have some
characteristics in common. For
example, all the worlds are staged
and all the men and women merely
players. Yeah, so you see the two,
like, worlds are staged and men and
women merely players. That is a
metaphor, so, yeah, it's staged. It
starts with the world, so the
world is a stage. And then we're
all players in it. But it's like this...
It's like that in the comparison,
because the world is not the stage.
But it's different from the
comparison. We'll talk about that
later too. An oxymoron
is used to create an effect
that
thinks of the opposite. Often, an
exymoron is
constructed by combining an adjective with
a noun.
For example, life and death. But
sometimes the contrasted
ideas are split out in the sentence.
So, to lead, you have to
go after. For example, I
find no peace and all my
war is finished. You say peace
and war, these are two mutual
ideas. I have fear and hope,
I burn and sound like ice. I flee
above the wind, yet I can not arise.
It's full of oxymorons. It's always
like fear and hope at the same time.
So in German. I worry and I
rejoice, for example. You can say that
in one sentence. That's
also an oxymoron.
Parallelism, Parallelismus, describes
use of components in a sentence that
are grim. Grammatically similar or
same in construction, sound and or
meaning. This leads to an impression
of balance and rhythm and the
repetition also conveys persu...
Sorry. Persu...ness. Also
conviction. I love thee freely as
men strive for right. I love thee
purely as they turn from praise. One
can see here as it is also... So
written directly after the motto.
This is the same structure. I love
thee. as So it is parallelism.
The opposite of parallelism
is chiasmus. So it's an inverted
parallelism. The type of words in
two other parallelisms is
inverted. Fair is foul. Foul is
fair. If you
write these two scenes , among the others,
you can
make a couple of crores. So
lazy is right and left and fair
is left and right. So you have
a crosse when you write it at the top
.
Yes, personality, you
probably know , is used to
connect human attributes to a thing, idea
or animal. And they imply that
non-human objects
feel or behave like human beings. For
example, the stars dance merrily in the
moonward quay. So, of course, stars
can't dance. But they are
personified, so now they can
dance. And that's also a
stylistic device. And that's
pretty easy to find, right?
So, if you have an analysis and
sometimes a poem is completely
personified, you can
write a lot about it. So, repetition,
that's again... Holung is when the
same words or phrases are repeated
more than once. It is often used to
make an idea clearer and more
memorable. So it makes sense. The
more often you hear something, the
better you can recognize it. Remember
it, sorry. For example. And that
government of the people, by the
people, for the people, shall not
perish from earth. So it is from
Abraham Lincoln, which was a
former... President of the United
States. So he puts emphasis on the
people. So government is all about
the people.
The rhetorical question, that means
that when a rhetorical question is
asked, there is no real answer. So it
is not expected to answer to the
question. It is solely asked for
effect or to emphasize a statement.
And often the answer is obvious. to
all of the people who are talking.
And this stylistic device is mainly
used as an impressive possessive
sorry, got problems with the word
today device. For example, if you
prick us, do we not bleed? If you
tickle us, do we not laugh? If you
poison us, do we not die? And if you
wrong us, shall we not revenge? So,
that's by Shakespeare. And yeah, you
see, so every... is not a question that
fights an answer, because the
answer is obvious.
For example, if you poison us,
don't we die? So, of course
you die then. But
you probably already know the rhetorical
question from other topics. So,
simulating is the comparison,
the comparisons . It is used to
compare oneself with different things and
to
show the comparisons . and in contrast to
a
metaphor, a simile uses the words
like or as or such as, hence a
comparison is a direct one. Here we
learned before that a metaphor is
implicit or indirect. For example,
elderly American ladies leaning on
the canes listed to warn me like
towers of pizza. You see the like,
that's a very, very safe indicator
for a simile, so quite easy.
Thank you for your attention.
Kajic up to here. Exactly. So now
I'm open to questions. If you want me
to explain something again or
explain something again in German
, right, now is the time
.
Or feedback or if you
say, yes please, I
don't really know anymore. Exactly. So
feedback is welcome, questions are
welcome.
If you don't have any questions, you'
re also welcome to say goodbye
, of course. Of course, you
don't have to stay in the room
unnecessarily long
.
No, okay, it's great that you were here.