Welcome to our webinar on useful
phrases for literary analysis. Today
we want to take a look at some
phrases you can use to write a
successful and enjoyable literary
analysis. For that we want to take a
look at how to use those phrases. So
the following phrases we are going to
show you can be used. um eine
Literarysen-Analyse zu schreiben. Man
sollte immer darauf achten, dass die
Wörter, die man benutzt, für den
Kontext ausreichend sind. Also
benutze sie nur, wenn es Sinn macht,
sie zu benutzen. Auch erinnere dich
daran, die Wörter zu variieren. Nimm
nicht immer die gleiche Wörter,
sondern nutze andere. Wir haben die
Wörter geteilt, die du benutzen
kannst. und zu vielen Themen. Also
heute lernt ihr über Phrasen für
Struktur und Plot, für Suspense,
Phrasen, die ihr für strukturelle
Geräte benutzen könnt, oder wenn ihr
über die Atmosphäre, die Sichtweise,
Phrasen, die ihr in Charakterisierung
benutzen könnt, und Phrasen, die ihr
benutzen könnt, um Sprache und Stil
zu beschreiben. We will begin with
structure and plot. So, some phrases
to describe the story or the plot
could be the plot thickens or the
story unfolds. The structure of the
story is loose and vague or it is
not, depending on your context. The
plot is complicated. The story
revolves. around something or the
story develops in the following way.
You could say the story moves towards
its climax or ending. The story nears
its end as an alternative to the
phrase before. The story is concluded
or the story is durch etwas beendet
wird, oder Plot und Charaktere
greifen die Aufmerksamkeit des
Lesers. Man könnte auch sagen, dass
die Geschichte gut geschrieben ist
oder nicht, was auch immer wahr ist.
Der Schreiber plotet eine gute
Geschichte heraus, oder die
Geschichte nimmt diverse Plot
-Richtungen. Now if you want to
describe the narrative or the
narrator, you could use phrases like
the narrative changes between the
present and the past, facts and
fiction merge in the tale, the writer
interweaves dream and reality, the
narrative is remarkable for the
excellence of individual scenes and
for its striking imagery. Der
Schauspieler verliert den Thread
seiner Diskussion. Der Schauspieler
wandert weg von seiner Geschichte.
Einige Phrasen für den Schauspieler
oder den Schauspieler. Der
Schauspieler nimmt den Thread des
Plotts ab. Der Schauspieler macht
selbstgehaltene Szenen. Oder
vielleicht schreibt der Schauspieler
die diversen Stücke seiner Geschichte
zusammen. Und wenn Sie die Theorie
beschreiben wollen, des Textes. Man
könnte sagen, dass die Hauptthemen
des Genres in der Geschichte
aufgelöst sind oder der Motiv durch
die Geschichte streicht. Das war es
für Struktur und Plot. Wir haben auch
einige Phrasen für Suspens. Einige
der üblichen Phrasen, die man
benutzen könnte, um über Suspens zu
sprechen, wären die Plot hält Suspens
oder der Suspens steigt zu seinem
Klimax. The author builds up suspense
by doing something or describing
something especially. The writer
draws out the suspense, so he delays
it. The decision of the protagonist
makes for considerable suspense. Or
the scene constitutes a high
watermark of suspense. Some
phrases for use on structural devices
would be Most of the story is given
over to flashbacks. The author
focuses on all previous events. We
could also use there are flashbacks
and foreshadowings. The author
introduces a digression. The writer
sets up a contrast between dark and
light. or there are hints as to the
nature of the events.
Phrases that describe the atmosphere
could be the surroundings provide a
highly atmospheric setting, the
author establishes an atmosphere of
doom, the atmosphere moves steadily
from reality to the supernatural, or
the author builds a powerful dense
atmosphere". So here you want to
describe how the author works with
the atmosphere in his text.
Some useful phrases to describe the
point of view could be the author
restricts our perspective to the
protagonist's point of view. So we
only know about the protagonist's
point of view and if we want to talk
Wir könnten diese Phrase benutzen
oder wir könnten sagen, dass die
Geschichte durch die Augen des
Protagonisten erzählt wurde, was im
Grunde die gleiche Bedeutung
bedeutet. Dann könnten wir Sätze wie,
es gibt eine deliberate Manipulation
der Verständnis der Redner von
Events, oder die Traine der Gedanken,
durch die der Protagonist seine
Schlussfolgerung zieht, sind ziemlich
logisch. Oder vielleicht ist es
illogisch. in the text or the play
you have to analyze.
For characterization, we can use
phrases like the writer analyzes the
emotional states of the main
character, the plot and character are
interwoven, the character changes in
the course of action, the characters
are well drawn and credible, each
character shows itself through talk,
Geist und Aktion oder die
Hauptcharakteristik des Protagonisten
ist, was auch immer die
Charakteristik ist, zum Beispiel, er
ist sehr wütend.
Einige Phrasen auf Sprache und Stil.
Der Schreiner expressiert sich in
Stil, Sprache, oder Englisch. Der
Schreiter macht den Einsatz von
formalen oder informellen Stilen oder
Sprache oder Englisch. Zum Beispiel.
Der Schreiter hat die Wahl von
Worten. Ist es akkurat, ist es
informal oder formal, ist es sehr
präzise oder ist es schriftlich. Der
Schreiter creates, for example, sad
feeling or sad mood or if you want to
use a different phrase for that, you
could say the writer achieves a sad
feeling or sad mood. The writer's
style can be defined as something or
the writer's style is characterized
by something.
So, with these phrases you can now
write an enjoyable analysis. You got
access to a lot of different phrases
now. You can use to write your
analysis. And it is important that
you vary these phrases and do not
always use the same one in order to
avoid a monotonous writing style.
Because readers won't enjoy your text
if you... repeat the same phrase all
over. Also was always very important
for analysis of all kind, you should
always use quotes from the text to
verify your statements. Because if
you don't it won't be a proper
analysis. And
with that we're at the end of today's
webinar. I want to thank you for your
attention and hope you have a noch
nicht.