Let's start with a little trip
through Edinburgh, telling you
something about the best tourist
attractions. The Edinburgh Castle is
one of the most visited tourist
attractions. The castle was built in
the 16th century on top of the castle
rock. Adults can visit the castle for
18 pounds 50, children from 5 to 15
years for 11 pounds 50. If you go to
Edinburgh, you will... You also have
to visit the Palace of Holyrood House
and Holyrood Abbey. It's the Queen's
residence. It was built in 1678. If
you like to, you can dress up in the
costumes in the family room. There's
a cafe where you can enjoy a tea or
coffee. Another place to visit is the
Royal Mile. It refers to the streets
linking Edinburgh Castle and the
Palace of Holyrood House. Es ist mit
schrecklichen Städten, historischen
Landmärkten und Kirchen verbunden. Es
ist ein großartiges Ort für Museen,
Cafés und Restaurants. Wenn Sie sich
aufbauen möchten, müssen Sie Arthur's
Seat besuchen, 820 Meter in dem
Hollywood Park. Auf dem Top haben Sie
eine spektakuläre Sicht über die
ganze Stadt. Eine Sache, die Sie für
frei in Edinburgh machen, ist das
Besuch des Nationalen Museums.
focusing on natural history, geology,
science and technology.