Hallo. Hallo. I would like a table
for two, please. Would you like to
eat outside or inside? Inside,
please. By the window. Sure. This
way, please. Great. Thanks. Here is
the menu. Would you like to drink
something? Yes. Two sparkling water,
please. Sure. What would you like to
eat? As a starter, I would like the
classic green salad. For the main
course, I would like the grilled ...
und für Dessert würde ich den
Tiramisu lieben. Und mein Freund
würde den Carpaccio als Starten
lieben, den homemade Tagliatelle mit
Pommes für den Hauptkurs und den
Schokoladenkuchen für Dessert. Was
anderes? Ja, bitte. Ich mag mein
Hauptessen spärmisch. Natürlich. Eine
Stunde später. Entschuldige, können
wir bitte den Konto haben? Hier ist
er. Würdest du zusammen oder separat
bezahlen? We would like to pay
together. Okay. That will be 54
pounds 50, please. Here you go. Thank
you.