Die Stadtwohnung von Wels ist
Cardiff. Es ist das perfekte Ort für
die Sichtsehenswürde und bekannt für
die am liebsten attraktiven Kastle.
Das erste Attraktionen, das ich Ihnen
präsentiere, ist das Cardiff Castle.
Jedes Zimmer ist voller nützlicher
Informationen über die Leute, die
damals dort lebten und dort
arbeiteten. Ein weiteres Highlight
dieses Castles ist die Clock Tower
und die Banqueting Hall, which is
famous for its rich artworks and
murals. Another good place to visit
is the Cardiff Bay. The Cardiff Bay
is one of the largest in Europe and
there are many fun things to do,
especially for kids. For example, the
Techniquest. It's an interactive and
kid-friendly science center. You can
spend hours walking the parks and
paths around the Cardiff Bay. For
those wanting to learn something
about the history of Wales, the
National Museum is a good place. It's
dealing with the country's history
all the way back to the time of
dinosaurs. The last thing I present
to you is the Principality Stadium.
If you're interested in sports, try
to take in a rugby match. When
there's no rugby game, the stadium is
often used for music artists.