The Beatles were an English rock
band, established in 1960 in
Liverpool. The band had four members,
and their names were Paul McCartney,
George Harrison, John Lennon and
Ringo Starr. With their first hit,
Love Me Do, in 1962, they became
popular in the UK. By 1964, the
Beatles had become international
stars, but unfortunately the band
decided to separate in 1970. due to
internal differences. Ten years
later, in 1980, John Lennon was
assassinated and George Harrison died
of cancer in 2001. Ringo Starr and
Paul McCartney continued playing
music. Together, the four members
were a record-breaking act and are
very important in pop music history.
They have sold more than 600 million
records and thus are the most
successful band und weltweit. Sie
haben den Namen The Fab Four erhoben.
Eine ihrer Songs, die Yesterday
heißt, ist die größte geschlossene
Song in der Geschichte. Andere
Beispiele einer well-known Song der
Band sind Let It Be und A Day in the
Life.